Sharon has...
なんば　むった
(南波六太)《シャロンが…》
Sharon has ALS...
エーエルエス
《あのシャロンがＡＬＳに!?》
《ダメだ…集中しろ！》
This isn't working. I can't concentrate...
《このテストは重要だ｡
わかってんのか!?》
This test is important... I should know that.
This test is important.
《このテストは重要》
I have to get a high score,
《ここで いい点取って
誰よりも早く➡
誰よりも先に選ばれないと
ダメだ！》
so I can hurry and reach the moon first!
《でないと…！》
(医師)では ここに連絡先を｡
Otherwise...
Then, please fill in their contact information.
Okay.
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)はい｡
あ…あれ？
Oh?
(医師)あ…いいです｡
私が書きますので番号を…｡
It's fine...
Just tell me, and I'll write it down.
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)あっ…はい｡
Sure.
《くっそ➡
Damn...
全然 頭に
入ってねぇじゃねぇか!!》
I don't know the answers.
(せりか)ＡＬＳは人によって
ちが
進行の速さも違って…➡
ALS progression varies from person to person.
１０年以上かけて
徐々に悪化する人もいれば➡
Some people may go ten years before symptoms worsen.
私の父のように
速い人もいます｡
But for some, like my father, it's much faster.
父は診断されてから
２年と１０ヶ月で亡くなりました｡
After my father's diagnosis, he lived for two years, ten months before passing away.
So don't worry... Just focus on your training, Mutta.
｢私の事は心配しないで
訓練 頑張ってね ムッタ｡➡
私も ３年後か４年後かに…➡
In three or four years,
ぼうえん
あなたに 月面望遠鏡計画の全ての
説明を伝えに行く予定です｡➡
I plan to head over, to brief you on the lunar telescope project.
覚えることだらけよ｡
覚悟はいい？｣｡
You'll have a lot to learn.
Are you prepared?
言ってくれるじゃないの ムッタ｡
That's the spirit, Mutta!
It's just obvious that the more you put in your bag
The heavier it gets
The harder I work, the closer I get to my goal
But I'm just not getting there fast enough
I gaze at the night sky but it doesn't calm me down
Now that you've heard how loud my heart's beating
Let's take a trip outside
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of dreams and reality
I'm currently updating the canvas of my dreams
With a glittering universe and a blue earth
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of facades and honesty
I'm currently conversing with the canvas of my dreams
On this orbit of fate
With a fire in my belly
#65 Wheelchair Pilot
⦅今の あなたにとって
一番 金ピカな事は何？⦆
Right now, what do you consider to be your shining star?
おれ
⦅今の俺にとって？⦆
Right now?
⦅さあ トランペットを持って
音を出して｡➡
Now, try playing the trumpet.
It's fine if it doesn't sound good.
うまくなくてもいいし
間違っててもいいのよ ムッタ｡➡
No one will blame you for making a mistake, Mutta.
まずは音を出して⦆
You need to try making noise first.
ふりゃっ｡
⦅できた！ハハハ⦆
I did it!
(キィーン ゴォォー)
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)はっし～ん！
Takeoff!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
(男)≪うわっ≫
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)≪フハハハ…！≫
(男)おわ！
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)おう！髪切った？
Hey, you cut your hair!
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)モーニン！
Morning!
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)おはよう！
Howdy!
ちくしょう まただよ｡
There he goes again.
あれだけ とばして よく誰にも
ぶつからないよな｡
I don't get how he has yet to hit anyone.
あ～いうのはヘタによけると
逆に危険ってもんだ｡
In any case, standing still is safer.
Good morning!
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)グッモーニン！
(試験官)ふあ～あ｡
(マイク)さて アスキャン諸君｡➡
Listen up, AsCans.
俺の親父がこんな名言を言った｡
My old man had a favorite monologue.
"Now look here, Mike...
｢いいか マイク｡空は いいぞぉ｡
パイロットになれ｡➡
The sky is real nice,
so become a pilot.
空を飛べない人生なんて
やつ
飛べる奴から見たら➡
Going through life without flying
ピクルスのないハンバーガー
みたいなもんだよ!!｣ってな！
is like eating a hamburger without pickles!"
《ピクルス程度の違いかよ》
That's it?
And so,
ティー
というわけで君らにＴ-３８の
操縦をたたきこんでくれる➡
I will now introduce the instructors who will teach you to fly the T-38.
しょうかい
飛行訓練教官を紹介しよう｡
ここにいる この６人だ！
The six gentlemen to my right!
Let's get some applause...
はくしゅ
ちが
はい 拍手～｡
違うよ マイク➡
You got it wrong, Mike.
７人だよ ７人！
Seven instructors... Seven.
Huh?
There's one more instructor.
もう１人いるでしょ 教官が｡
あ～まあ 確かに
もう１人いることは いるんだが➡
Oh...
Yeah, I guess there's one more instructor.
そいつは どう考えても
せいいっぱい
１人教えるので精一杯の➡
But we're talking about a geezer who can barely handle one student.
老いぼれじいさんだ｡
I would focus on the six present.
メインは この６人だと
思ってくれていい｡
マイクさん！そのじいさん教官に
ぴったりのアスキャンがいますよ｡
Mike, we have the perfect AsCan for the old man...
ついし
今１人で追試 受けてるヤツ｡
The only one who needed a make-up exam.
(ｱｽｷｬﾝ)アッハハハ！
(ｱｽｷｬﾝ)ムッタね｡
Mutta, huh?
あいつの点数 見た？
ちょっとひいちゃったぜ｡
Did you see his score?
I was pretty shocked.
確かに あれはマズイよな｡
Yeah, it really was that bad.
アスキャンにまで
残った者が取る点じゃない｡
An AsCan shouldn't perform so poorly after coming this far.
(ｱｽｷｬﾝ)普通に本 読んでりゃ
５０点は取れる｡➡
If you just read the material, you can score over 50 easily.
なのに たったの…｡
にった
(新田)おい｡
But somehow, he managed to—
Hey...
その辺にしといたら どうだ｡
I think that's enough.
お おいおい 大げさだな｡
Come on, no need to be so serious...
《がんばって…南波さん！》
Good luck,
Nanba.
よ～し 終わりだ｡ペンを置いて｡
All right, time's up.
Pencils down.
つか
お疲れ 行っていいぞ｡
はい｡
Good work.
You're free to go.
Okay.
《なんとか集中できた》
I managed to stay focused.
《やったぜ…シャロン…》
I did it, Sharon...
はっは！
《わかったぜ｡➡
I've got it now...
集中だ 集中！俺から
集中を取ったら➡
The key is focus...
That's the only thing I have going for me.
一体 何が残るというのだ》
(男)わあ！
《集中さえ できれば
俺は何だってできるんだ！》
If I can stay focused, I can do anything!
(男)おわっ！
Doesn't matter what they throw at me...
これからだって そうだ｡
(男)おわっ｡
(男)≪わあ！≫
Huh?
うっく…！
ぐわあ…いてててて！
チクショー！何でだぁ？
Damn, why me?
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)大丈夫か？➡
You okay?
You're the first person who moved in the same direction I did...
ワシが かわす方向に よけて
きたのは お前が初めてだ｡➡
A NASA cap...
ぼう
《ＮＡＳＡ帽…！➡
Rolex.
ロラックス…！➡
歯抜け…！➡
Missing tooth.
デニール･ヤング！》
Deneil Young!
Hey, Alexander.
おう！アレクサンダー｡
おう アレクサンダー｡
Hey, Alexander.
⦅ハァ ハァ ハァ…⦆
⦅アポ～！どこ行った～！⦆
Apo! Where did you go?
⦅おう！久しぶりだな➡
Oh?
It's been ages, Alexander.
アレクサンダー
乗ってくか？お？⦆
Want a ride?
⦅ハァ ハァ ハァ…
アレクサンダー？⦆
Alexander?
⦅見ろ ムッタ｡リフトオフだ⦆
Look, Mutta.
We have liftoff.
⦅うわぁ～っ⦆
Wow....
⦅ま…まっぶっし～!!⦆
It's blinding.
⦅ところで ムッタ
｢空｣と｢人生｣の一番の違いは➡
By the way, Mutta...
Do you know the biggest difference between life and the sky?
何だか知ってるか？お？➡
｢空｣は誰のもんでもない｡
｢人生｣は自分のもんだ｡➡
The sky doesn't belong to anyone.
Your life belongs to you.
｢人生｣はコントロールがきく⦆
You can control your own life.
⦅もし お前が
宇宙飛行士に選ばれたら➡
If you're selected as an astronaut, the next time we meet
次にワシと会うのは…プッ！
飛行場だ｡イエ～イ！⦆
will be at the airfield.
Yay.
ヤ…ヤングじいさん…｡
Mr. Young...
同じ方向に よけてくるとは…
なかなかのギャグ人間だな➡
After watching you move in the same direction I did,
I'd say you have the talent to become a comedian, Alexander.
アレクサンダー！ハハハハッ！
だから
アレクサンダーじゃねえって！
My name isn't Alexander!
Who is that, anyway?
誰だよ それ｡３ヶ月ぐらいで
もう俺のこと忘れたか!?
After three months, you've already forgotten?
お？違った？あ～あれか｡
Oh? The wrong person?
Oh, I know!
なんだっけ…ヌッタ？違うな…｡
You're, uh...
Nutta?
No, that's wrong...
ちょっと待て 今ここまで
出てるんだ｡え～と～…｡
Just a moment... It's on the tip of my tongue.
Let's see...
ラッタ！
ムッタ！
Ratta!
Mutta!
ムッタか！ハハハッ！
短くて覚えやすい名だ！
Mutta, huh?
A short name that's easy to remember.
《覚えてね～じゃね～か》
You couldn't remember it...
ついて来い ムッタ｡
Come with me, Mutta.
Hmm?
なあ 足どうしたんだよ ヤンじい｡
いつから車イスに？
Say...
What happened to your legs?
When did you first need a wheelchair?
あれっ ちょっと!?
Huh?
Hold on...
はえ
速っ！
He's fast!
ちょっと！待って！
Hey, wait up!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
早く乗れ ムッタ 閉めるぞ｡
Hurry, Mutta, before the door closes.
Huh?
ふお～っ！
ハァ ハァ…｡
最高だろ このバギー｡➡
This buggy rocks...
しよう
ちょいとワシ仕様に改造してある｡
I had it customized.
キャンディーなめるか？お？
Want some candy? Huh?
３０秒しかウマくないやつだろ？
That's the kind that's only good for thirty seconds, right?
じゃあ…
新発売の天国ガムはどうだ？➡
Then, how about some new Heavenly Gum?
The taste only lasts twenty seconds,
こいつは２０秒しか味がねえが➡
その２０秒間は…天国だぜ？
but you get twenty seconds of heaven!
とうちゃく
クチャクチャ…｡
じゃあ ２０秒後には
吐き出すんだな？
So you'll spit it out in twenty seconds?
出すわけねぇだろ｡２０秒後には➡
No way.
In twenty seconds, it'll be bubble-blowing heaven for me.
フーセン天国で
遊べるんだぜ｡ウハハハハ！
《いよいよ
こいつに乗るんだな…》
I finally get to ride in a jet.
おっと こいつのことは
知ってるか？Ｔ-３８｡
Oh, do you know much about the T-38?
It's the plane they use to train USAF and NASA pilots.
空軍同様 宇宙飛行士も
この機体で飛行訓練をする｡➡
When you fly this plane, you need to check weather conditions,
そうじゅう
操縦しながら風向きやら天気を
チェックしたり➡
地面を見たり
管制と やりとりしたりな｡➡
keep your eye on the ground,
and perform other operational tasks.
同時に あれこれこなせなきゃ
宇宙飛行士には…➡
If you aren't able to multitask while flying, you can't become an astronaut.
向かねえってこった｡ハハハハッ！
《ん？なんだ？このサンパチ…》
What's with this T-38?
《穴…あいてる…》
There's a hole...
ほら 外行くぞ ムッタ｡
Come on... Let's move outside, Mutta.
他のアスキャン達が
飛ぶ準備してる｡
The other AsCans are getting ready to fly.
プゥ～！
教官のパイロットの中にも➡
The pilot instructors
密かにランクがあってな…｡
are secretly ranked.
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)言ってみりゃ
生徒達からの人気順だ｡➡
It's more or less based on popularity with students.
That's determined by things like how nice they act, how good they are at teaching,
教え方がうまいとか優しいとか➡
or how sexy their voice is on the radio.
無線で聞く声がセクシーだとかな｡
There's little difference in terms of flying ability.
パイロットの腕前に関しては
大差はない｡➡
あいつら みんな一流だ｡
They're all top class...
まぁ ワシは超一流だけどな！
ウハッハッハハハ！
But I'm super top class.
But you probably aren't very popular.
《でも 人気なさそ～っ》
プゥ～！
Congratulations.
おめでとう｡実におめでとう｡➡
Congratulations to everyone.
The AsCans with the best scores are assigned to the best instructors.
成績優秀なアスキャンには
それに見合った➡
すぐ
優れた教官が担当につく
というものなんだよ｡
実に良かったね｡好成績の
君達５人は実に当たりだよ｡
You're very lucky.
As you five had the top scores, you've hit the jackpot.
私が担当のｱﾚｸｻﾝﾀﾞｰ･ﾆｺﾗｽ･ﾌｨﾘｯﾎﾟｽ･
ﾒﾃﾞｨﾅｶﾛｽだ｡よろしく｡
I'm Alexander Nikolas Phillipos Medinakalos.
Nice to meet you.
(一同)よろしくお願いします｡
It's a pleasure to meet you.
なげ
《長ぇな…名前とか…顔とか…》
That's a really long name...
And a long face.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)《ムッ君っぽい…》
Reminds me of Mu.
《あ…そういえば南波さん
追試 終わったかな…》
Oh, I wonder if Nanba finished taking his test.
昔は そんな仕組みでも
なかったんだけどな｡➡
It wasn't always like this...
知らん間に…できる生徒に
ランクの高い教官をつけて➡
But along the way, they adopted the practice of assigning better instructors to better students.
優先的に伸ばしていく
方式になった｡➡
ちなみにワシは最低ランクだ！
《やっぱり》
And I was always at the bottom of the list.
I knew it.
なんせ ワシの操縦に耐えられる
生徒がおらんからな！ハハハハ！
After all, none of the students could endure my flying.
ムッタはテストどうだった？お？
How did you do on the test? Eh?
Well, I was the only one who needed a make-up.
まぁ…さっき１人で
追試を受けたよね｡
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)そうか！ウハハハ！
そういえば ヤンじいは➡
Really?
That's right... You mentioned you taught Hibito to fly.
ひびと
日々人に操縦 教えたって
言ってたよな｡
そうだ！日々人もテストで
最低点を取ったからな！
I did.
That's because Hibito also had the lowest score on the test.
ワシが担当になった｡
So I was assigned to him.
《あのヤロー…フツーに
勉強さぼりやがったな》
That fool...
I bet he didn't study.
Hey, they're getting ready to fly.
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)おっ！いよいよ飛ぶか｡➡
見ろ 後ろに１人
アスキャンが乗り込んでる｡
ケンジだ！
Look, there's an AsCan getting in the back.
It's Kenji!
もうちょっと上に座って｡
はい｡
Try to sit higher.
Yes, sir.
この酸素コネクターで酸素
こっちの通信コネクターを➡
This connector is for oxygen.
If you use the comm connector here,
つなげば 俺や管制と話が
できるようになる｡いいな｡
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)はい｡
you can speak to me and Ground Control.
Got it?
Yes, sir.
チクショー いいな～！
Man, lucky bastard...
さあ ショータイムだ｡
Now, it's show time.
Wow...
すげえ！
はええ～！
もう あんなに小っちぇえ！
So fast! It's already out of sight!
来い ムッタ｡
This way, Mutta.
Huh?
ワシ専用のＴ-３８がある｡➡
I have my own personal T-38.
こっそり ジェットエンジンを
改造した｡
I secretly modified the jet engine.
すいしんりょく
推進力が他の１.５倍だ｡
ラムジェットエンジン並だぞ！
It has 1.5 times the propulsion of the other jets.
Power on the level of ramjet engines!
《なんでもかんでも
改造しやがって》
He should stop customizing everything.
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)さて｡
Now, then...
《歩けんのかよ!!》
You can walk?!
Here's your helmet.
オマエのヘルメットだ｡かぶれ｡
Put it on.
ワシについて来られるなら➡
If you can keep up with me,
you'll progress 1.5 times faster than everyone else.
他の奴の１.５倍
早く仕上げてやるぞ｡フフッ！
It's been so long since I looked up at the moon
Though it's always keeping a cold eye on me
Yeah, it always keeps a cold eye on me
I wanna rough up this rotten way home
But even it makes me mad
I can't take my eyes off. Yeah, I can't take my eyes of it
I can't take my eyes off that dazzling smile
What did I want back then?
What was I looking for?
I should've known my tears would take me to my dreams
Blow this gloomy reality away for me
I want to see how tiny our huge worries seem
From up in that dark ocean of space
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#66 Two Notebooks
It's show time!
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)＜ｼｮｰﾀｲﾑだ！ウハハ！＞
＜いきなり アクロバット飛行!?＞
He's starting me with aerobatics?
Everyone throws up after their first flight.
(ﾃﾞﾆｰﾙ)＜初めて ワシと
同乗した奴は必ず吐く｡➡
頭のノートにメモっとけ＞
Put that down in the notebook in your head.
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Two Notebooks"